{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "1. In a mixture of the four proteins listed below, which would elute second in size exclusion chromatography",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Cytochrome- 13kDa",
        "b": "Immunoglobulin- 14.5 kDa",
        "c": "Ribonuclease- 13.7 kDa",
        "d": "RNA polymerase â€“ 45 kDa"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "2. What are the important factors to be considered while preparing buffer for size exclusion chromatography?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Buffer must be compatible with protein stability and activity",
        "b": "Buffer must be degassed",
        "c": "Buffer must be filtered",
        "d": "All of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "3. Which is the best size exclusion chromatographic media for high resolution, short run time and high recovery?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Sephadex",
        "b": "Superose",
        "c": "Sephacryl",
        "d": "Superdex"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Superdex media is made by",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Cross-linking dextran",
        "b": "Cross linking dextran with agarose",
        "c": "Cross-linking porous agarose",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "5. Analytical size exclusion chromatography is used for",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Desalting",
        "b": "Check the quality of the sample",
        "c": "Isolate one or more components from a sample",
        "d": "All of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Which of the following chromatographic resin is used for desalting and buffer exchange?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Sephadex",
        "b": "Superose",
        "c": "Sephacryl",
        "d": "Superdex"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "7. What can be the possible reasons behind protein molecules not eluting as expected?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Column is not equilibrated properly",
        "b": "Protein has precipitated on the column",
        "c": "Column is overloaded with sample",
        "d": "All of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "8. What can cause low recovery of protein activity but normal recovery of protein molecules after purification using size exclusion chromatography?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Protein molecule is unstable or inactive in the buffer used",
        "b": "Protein has been degraded by proteases",
        "c": "Column is not equilibrated properly",
        "d": "High flow rate of buffer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "9. The eluted protein fractions after performing size exclusion chromatography can be analyzed using",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Agarose gel electrophoresis",
        "b": "EMSA",
        "c": "SDS PAGE",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "10. Which of the following solution can be used for cleaning size exclusion chromatography column?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "1M NaOH",
        "b": "30 % Isopropanol",
        "c": "Both (a) and( b)",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    }
  ]
}
